import { Category } from 'src/app/interfaces/category.interface';

export default {
  name: 'Алфавит (латиница)',
  cards: [
    {
      question: 'A a',
      answer: '[a]',
    },
    {
      question: 'B b',
      answer: '[б]',
    },
    {
      question: 'V v',
      answer: '[в]',
    },
    {
      question: 'G g',
      answer: '[г]',
    },
    {
      question: 'D d',
      answer: '[д]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Đ đ',
      answer: 'мягкое [дж] мягкая д и как бы мягкая ж',
    },
    {
      question: 'E e',
      answer: '[э]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Ž ž',
      answer: '[ж]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Z z',
      answer: '[з]',
    },
    {
      question: 'I i',
      answer: '[и]',
    },
    {
      question: 'J j',
      answer: '[й]',
    },
    {
      question: 'K k',
      answer: '[к]',
    },
    {
      question: 'L l',
      answer: '[л]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Lj lj',
      answer: '[ль]',
    },
    {
      question: 'M m',
      answer: '[м]',
    },
    {
      question: 'N n',
      answer: '[н]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Nj nj',
      answr: '[нь]',
    },
    {
      question: 'O o',
      answer: '[о]',
    },
    {
      question: 'P p',
      answer: '[п]',
    },
    {
      question: 'R r',
      answer: '[р]',
    },
    {
      question: 'S s',
      answer: '[с]',
    },
    {
      question: 'T t',
      answer: '[т]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Ć ć',
      answer: 'мягкое [ч]',
    },
    {
      question: 'U u',
      answer: '[у]',
    },
    {
      question: 'F f',
      answer: '[ф]',
    },
    {
      question: 'H h',
      answer: '[х]',
    },
    {
      question: 'C c',
      answer: '[ц]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Č č',
      answer: 'твёрдое [ч] как бы между ТШ',
    },
    {
      question: 'Dž dž',
      answer: 'твёрдое [дж] (как в слове джем)',
    },
    {
      question: 'Š š',
      answer: '[ш]',
    },
  ],
} as Category;

